Surely many of you who are
seguramente a muchos de los que estáis
entering this video are going to feel a little
entrando en este vídeo os pase un poco
like me. You are going to discover in this
como a mí que Vais a descubrir en este
video you have just discovered what
vídeo acabáis de descubrir lo que
the term trat Wi means. And it is that
significa el término trat Wi Y es que
lately it is very fashionable to
últimamente está como muy de moda
give these spangl names to a
ponerles estos nombres spangl a un
lot of things and to pigeonhole things
montón de cosas y encasillar las cosas
with these types of terms with how easy it
con este tipo de términos con lo fácil
would be to mention traditional woman
que sería mencionar mujer tradicional
traditional family. But anyway, this
familia tradicional Pero bueno Este
term has become very
término últimamente se ha puesto muy de
fashionable lately and is on many people's lips. It is a
moda y está en Boca de mucha gente Es un
term that is becoming quite
término que se está haciendo bastante
viral and is being talked about a lot, for
viral y se está comentando mucho por
example in cases like rorro rorro
ejemplo por casos como el de rorro rorro
is an influencer who has gone very
es una influencer que se ha hecho muy
viral Last week while I
viral La semana pasada mientras que yo
was on vacation that's why there was no
estaba de vacaciones por eso no hubo
video because she was taking great care of her boyfriend, I mean
vídeo por eh cuidar mucho a su novio o
literally just like that, I'm not going
sea literalmente así tal cual no me voy
to dwell on the rorro issue because you already
a explayar con el tema rorro porque ya
have some clicks on my Twitter from
tenéis algunos clicks en mi Twitter de
people giving their opinion on this issue in a bad way,
gente opinando sobre este tema para mal
like for example the feminist Abi what
como por ejemplo la feminista Abi qué
happened to rorro The problem is
qué ha ocurrido con rorro El problema es
that a video of her came out in which she
que salió un vídeo de ella en el que
spoke with a normal voice, that is to say, it was
hablaba con una voz nor es decir que se
shown that the voices she uses  in
demostró que las voces que pone en
Oy Pablo's videos he felt like it's a
vídeos de Oy a Pablo le apetecía es una
forced voice And what happens with this whole
voz forzada Y qué ocurre con todo este
concept of a woman with a slightly
concepto de mujer con voz así un poquito
childish voice H
infantil H
very that what all the videos do is
muy que lo que hacen todos los vídeos es
give to her partner like What is the
dar a su pareja en plan Cuál es la
word provide Exactly eh conscious
palabra proveer Exacto eh consciente
pleases her partner what happens with
complace a a su pareja qué ocurre con
all this moving that you know that Ah
todo este moviendo que ya sabes que Ah
classically the woman has been there to
clásicamente la mujer ha estado para eso
serve her partner kitchen eh you
para servir a la pareja cocina eh tú
want I'll give you today Pablo has
quieres yo te doy hoy a Pablo le ha
felt like such everything has been said that I
apetecido tal todo se ha dicho que yo
think this was more of a format that
creo que esto fue más un formato que le
worked for her and that's why she has abused it
funcionó a ella y por eso lo ha abusado
than the fact that she is
que el hecho de que ella esté intentando
actively trying to promote the
activamente promover el mujer
traditional woman I want to be this is the best you
tradicional quiero ser esto es lo mejor
know it's not so much Trade wfe but I think
sabes no es tan Trade wfe sino creo que
it's a format that worked for her and she abused it
es un formato que le funcionó y lo abuso
what happens What I think that everything
de él qué ocurre Qué creo que todo se
can be criticized and have an opinion about it
puede criticar y opinar al respecto
from a somewhat objective way and
desde una manera un poco objetiva y
even if it is a format that
aunque sea un formato que eso que le
worked for her benefited her it's okay she's not
funcionó le benefició está bien no le
harming anyone eh For my
está haciendo daño a nadie eh Para mi
way of seeing it yes it is
manera de verlo sí que le está haciendo
harming Well everything we've been through such that
daño a Pues todo por lo que llevamos tal
she  you can do it perfectly
que ella lo puede hacer sí perfectamente
but it is true that this set is quite
pero sí que es cierto que es bastante
strange today my girlfriend
raro el conjunto este de hoy a m novia
wanted to and I'm going to do it with a
le apetecía y le voy a hacer con voz
super little girl voice and all and the worst thing is that
super de niña pequeña y tal y lo pero es
then she comes out in interviews and she keeps
que sale luego en entrevistas y sigue
putting on this voice or she comes out in podcasts and she
poniendo esta voz o saleen podcast y
keeps putting on this voice that is not her voice like we've already
sigue poniendo esta voz que no es su voz
seen personal videos of hers
en plan ya se ha visto vídeos personales
that are not her voice So why do they
suyos que no es su voz Entonces por qué
put it on Why why do they try so hard to
la ponen Por qué por qué intenta tanto
give this image of Chiquitita such a voice or
dar esta imagen de Chiquitita tal voz o
people who have been more applauded like for
gente que ha sido más aplaudida como por
example the chocas I spend 4 hours to make
ejemplo el chocas yo 4 horas para hacer
a taco why Well because I'm like
un taco por qué Pues porque yo soy como
roro I work hard on the food and I make it with
roro yo me curro la comida y la hago con
love and this is something that many of
amor y esto es algo que muchos de
you don't understand I suppose that the
vosotros no lo entendéis Supongo que la
la la the people who criticize this this
la la la gente que critica a esta a esta
Poor girl will be the same ones who
Pobre muchacha será las mismas que
criticize that the models work
critican el que el que modelos trabajen
in Formula 1 eh To open the race
en la Fórmula 1 eh Para abrir la carrera
because women are sexualized sexualize
porque se sexualiza la mujer sexualizar
what friend are women who live off their
el qué amigo son mujeres que viven de su
image just like actors and actresses
imagen igual que los actores y actrices
or just like models live off their clown image love
o igual que los modelos viven de su
yourself a little  [ __ ] what
imagen payasa quiérete un poco [__] qué
are you saying Well of course they are
estás diciendo Pues claro que están
happy to work for formula
encantadas de trabajar para la fórmula
one and earn a lot of money thanks to their body that's why they
un y cobar una pasta gracias a su cuerpo
take care of it [ __ ] yeah why do they
para eso se lo cuidan cabrón sio para
go to the gym six days a week
que van seis días a la semana al
but what are we talking about
gimnasio pero de qué estamos hablando
dude It's that you have to be whatever they want you ca
colega Es que es que tú tienes que ser
n't
lo que a ellas les salga del no puedes
be whatever you want because your freedom
ser lo que tú quieras porque tu libertad
doesn't exist that women of today can't
no existe que las mujeres de hoy no
cook that you can't do what
pueden cocinar que tú no puedes hacer lo
you want girl you have to do
que tú quieras tía tú tienes que hacer
what we tell you that
lo que nosotras te digamos que no lo
the poor roro doesn't understand it that you
está entendiendo la pobre roro que tú
do what we tell you roro
haces lo que nosotras te digamos roro
that you can't be free You have to
que tú no puedes ser libre Tú te tienes
empower yourself let your husband cook [ __ ] that is
que empoderar que cocine tu marido [__]
empowering yourself Of course man it is
eso es empoderarte Claro que sí hombre
wrong to cook [ __ ] cooking is
que está mal cocinar [__] cocinar es
for slaves don't let anyone tell you otherwise
de esclavas que no te digan lo contrario
Of course man don't do whatever the
Claro que sí hombre tú no hagas lo que
[ __ ] you want eh do what they
te salga del [__] eh haz lo que ellas te
tell you yes yes feminism of my Holy [ __ ] it is that
digan sí sí feminismo de mi Santo [__]
but really that they make the
es es ese pero de verdad que tomen la
decision to separate know how to differentiate
decisión de separarse saber diferenciar
well what progressivism is from that
bien lo que es el progresismo a esa
garbage because the left is a
basura porque la izquierda es una parte
very  important in society and if it gets
muy importante de la sociedad y como se
together with extremists they'll go to
junte con los extremistas se van a la
[ __ ] look at having transformed a
[__] mira que haber transformado a un
movement as important as
movimiento tan importante como el
feminism into this garbage
feminis como el feminismo en esta basura
is one of the greatest
es una de las mayores vergüenzas
social shames that I have experienced in my country in
sociales que he vivido en mi país en
my entire life and it does not represent the
toda mi vida y no representa el
feminism that they want
feminismo que a ellas les sale del [__]
feminism is what they say not the
el feminismo es lo que ellas dicen no la
freedom of women and equality and
libertad de las mujeres y la igualdad y
equality before the law which is what
la igualdad ante la ley que es lo que
feminism really seeks It seems
busca realmente el feminismo Me parece
bestial to me that this woman can't do whatever she wants
bestial que esta mujer no pueda hacer lo
no she can't
que le dé la gana que no que no se puede
cook she's a woman How about making
cocinar que es mujer Cómo que hacer unas
croquettes roro no croquettes or dicks don't
croquetas roro ni croquetas ni pollas no
do what you like you'll do what
hagas lo que te gusta harás lo que
we tell you Welcome to
nosotros te digamos Bienvenido al
modern feminism You will do what we
feminismo moderno Tú harás lo que te
tell you and shut up This is how we speak
digamos nosotros y callada Así se habla
very well very well really about this
muy bien muy bien realmente sobre este
debate I think that it's not about
debate Yo pienso que no se trata de que
things being right or wrong but about
las cosas estén bien o estén mal sino de
each person deciding how to live their life and
que cada uno decida cómo vivir su vida y
as long as they do so under a freedom
siempre que lo haga bajo una libertad
that each person be it the husband or the
que cada persona sea el marido o la
wife has chosen Well there is no  The
mujer haya escogido Pues no hay ningún
problem is that there are people who like
problema hay gente a la que le gusta
certain types of relationships and people who are
unos tipos de relaciones y gente que son
happier living a more
más felices llevando un tipo de vida más
traditional lifestyle. When we talk about
tradicional cuando hablamos de estas
traditional families that assume and
familias tradicionales que asumen y Def
defend the gender roles of each
defienden estos roles de género de cada
individual within the couple, we're talking about the
uno dentro de la pareja hablamos de la
typical one where the man leaves home to make a
típica que el hombre sale de casa a
living, he comes
buscarse la vida llega cansado el
home tired because he's burdened with the entire
trabajo porque carga con toda la
economy of the family of the future, and the
economía de la familia del futuro y la
woman who takes care of the house, who takes care of
mujer que cuida de la casa que cuida de
the children, who takes care of the husband, and who
los niños que cuida del marido y que lo
has everything under control in this regard, it
tiene todo controlado respecto a esto a
seems to me that there should be little
mí me parece que debería haber poco
debate in the sense that I'm telling you, I
debate en el sentido de lo que os digo o
mean, eh, I understand that when a
sea eh Yo entiendo que cuando un
married couple decides to live together,
matrimonio deciden irse a vivir juntos
start a family, or simply a
formar una familia o simplemente una
couple that doesn't have children but decides to
pareja que no tenga hijos pero decida
plan the type of relationship they're going to
planificar el tipo de relación que van a
have and the future or what awaits them,
tener y el futuro o qué les espera
as long as they both agree on
mientras que ambos estén de acuerdo en
what each one is going to fulfill, what would be
lo que va a cumplir cada uno cuál sería
the problem? Maybe within a
el problema a lo mejor dentro de una
couple, one of the two, whether it's the man or
pareja uno de los dos ya sea el hombre o
the woman, bears the burden of bringing
sea la mujer carga con el peso de traer
money home and the other, whether it's the
el dinero a casa y el otro ya sea el
man or the woman, takes care of the
hombre o la mujer se ocupa de las tareas
household chores and takes care of many things that
del hogar y se ocupa de muchas cosas que
may be the same.  or more exhausting
pueden ser igual o más agotadoras
tired than the actual job itself
cansadas que el mismísimo trabajo por
So I think it's about
cuenta ajena Así que yo creo que se
sharing out the tasks a little bit so that it's
trata de repartirse un poco las tareas
a fair distribution that both
de que sea un reparto justo de que ambos
respect each other that each one does what they
se respeten de que cada uno haga lo que
feel they're good at because
considere que se le dé bien porque a lo
maybe man or woman one of the
mejor hombre o mujer a uno de los los
two likes to cook maybe the other is
dos le gusta cocinar a lo mejor a otro
terrible at it as long as it's not
se le da fatal siempre que no se trate
an issue of sexist abuse and
de un tema de abuso de machismo y
basically a lack of shame in the
básicamente de poca vergüenza en las
last few hours
últimas horas se está viralizando mucho
the case of balerina Farm is going viral which is good if you don't
El caso de balerina Farm que bueno si no
know who she is because she's an
sabéis quién es porque se trata de una
influencer who's really making it big
influencer que lo está petando muchísimo
English speaking balerina Farm will surely
anglo parlante balerina Farm seguramente
sound familiar to you And the thing is that the name really
te sonará Y es que realmente el nombre
sounds like a brand of ballet flats or
suena como una marca de balletas o de
floor cleaners quite an
fregasuelos chiste bastante
unfortunate joke considering that we're
desafortunado teniendo en cuenta que
going to talk about a woman who has to
vamos a hablar de una mujer que tiene
be grateful because her husband
que estar agradecida porque su marido le
gave her a
regale un
myth present from
myth present from
danel
danel
Where It Off took It Off from
Where It Off took It Off from
[Music] ukraine
[Música]
so A Hat I can Wear
so A Hat I can Wear
in not hat not ah [
in not hat not ah
Applause]
[Aplausos]
myome balerina  Farm victim or
myome balerina Farm víctima o
privileged we debate it in this video I
privilegiada lo debatimos en este vídeo
tell you the whole true story behind
os cuento toda la historia real detrás
Hann New Lindman who is What is
de hann New lindman que es Cómo se llama
the girl's name with all the details like no one has ever told you before make yourself comfortable and enjoy the video What's up my kids welcome one more day to my channel I'm Javi Olveira you already know that here we found out the queen of strat Wi a new trend in networks that pigeonholes
nueva tendencia en redes que encasilla
housewives where the father would be the
las amas de casa donde el padre sería el
provider it is assumed that Hann known on
proveedor se supone que hann conocida en
networks as Valerina Farm abandoned her
redes como valerina Farm abandonó sus
dreams of being a professional dancer to
sueños de c bailarina profesional para
end up living on a farm with her
terminar viviendo en una granja con su
husband taking care of all the
su esposo encargándose de todo el
work with the animals with the cleaning
trabajo con los animales con la limpieza
and their eight children there aot of
y de sus ocho hijos there aot of
sacrifices there's emotional sacrifices
sacrifices there's emotional sacrifices
And there's physical I grew up in the
And there's physical I grew Up In the
city indoors I danced all day long in studios I didn't
city indoors I danced all day long in
know what it meant to be a farmer or raise
Studios I didn't know what it meant to
animals for one
be a farmer or raise animals for One
reason or another and we both loved the
Reason or another dan both loved the
idea of raising our children on a farm
idea of raising Our children On A farm
and it was this dream that we talked
and It was this Dream that we talked
about and we talked about and finally it
about and we talked about and Finally it
got to the point Where we Had to
got to the point Where we Had to
[Music]
[Música]
in recent days the case is going
en los últimos días el caso se está
viral Apart from the fact that this
viralizando Aparte de porque esta
family moves a lot on YouTube,
familia mueve muchísimo tanto en YouTube
Instagram and TikTok because
como en instagram como en tikt porque
Well, these types of issues are being
Bueno este tipo de cuestiones se están
debated a lot
poniendo mucho a debate sobre la mesa en
lately, it's a topic that is
los últimos tiempos es un tema que está
very fashionable and they also just gave an
muy de moda y además acaban de dar una
interview for the Times I didn't always
entrevista para the Times no siempre
want this life I left home at
quise esta vida me fui de casa a los 17
17 and I was excited to arrive in
años y estaba emocionada de llegar a
New York I loved the energy of the
Nueva York Me encantaba la energía de la
city and I wanted to be a dancer, I was good
ciudad y quería ser bailarina era buena
Surely you have heard about the
Seguramente se has escuchado hablar del
subject or I have seen some criticism they are
tema o he visto alguna crítica se están
sitting down to point out that this woman has
sentando en señalar que esta señora ha
abandoned her dreams of being a
abandonado sus sueños de ser bailarina
professional dancer because her husband has her
profesional porque su marido la tiene
caged in a kind of
enjaulada en una especie de cárcel de
golden prison and they call it a golden prison because the
oro y lo llaman cárcel de oro porque la
truth is that they are getting rich
verdad es que se están forrando les van
things are going quite well for them In fact I would
las cosas bastante bien De hecho yo
say much more than if she
diría que muchísimo más que si se
had dedicated herself to being a
hubiera dedicado a hac una bailarina
professional dancer But well that's a matter of taste, maybe
profesional Pero bueno eso para gustos
you think
colores no a lo mejor ustedes pensáis
that not everything is about money and others think that it is
que no todo es el dinero y otros pensáis
Well we'll see and this
que sí Bueno ya lo veremos y esta jaula
golden cage  It would be the farm where they live
de oro sería la granja en la que viven
in the state of Utad which is a state
en el estado de utad que es un estado
within the United States of America
dentro de los Estados Unidos de América
and this has partly led her to be in
y esto En parte le ha llevado a ser en
recent weeks one of the
las últimas semanas una de las
most harassed influencers insulted
influencers más acosadas insultadas
criticized at the same time that it is supposed that she is
criticadas a la vez que se supone que es
more defended happening a bit like what happened to
más defendida pasando un poco como lo de
the girl that we have been mentioning at the
la chica que hemos estado mencionando al
beginning of the roro video that has come
inicio del vídeo roro que ha llegado a
out on all the televisions at
salir en todas las televisiones por lo
least nationally I don't know in
menos de tirada nacional no sé en
your countries harassed for being a
vuestros países acosada por ser ama de
housewife harassed by animal rights activists because she is
casa acosada por animalistas porque se
dedicated to raising animals and making her
dedica a criar animales y hacerse su
own meat her own food
propia carne sus propios alimentos lo
which is a farm harassed for
que viene a ser una granja acosada por
being a beauty queen which yes that is
ser reina de belleza que eso sí que eso
rarely mentioned but she continues
sí poco se menciona Pero sigue
to participate in the contest in fact
participando en certamen de hecho el año
last year she won harassed for promoting
pasado ganó acosada por promover el
Christianity and being very religious harassed
cristianismo y ser muy religiosa acosada
for promoting rodeo and harassed for
por promover el rodeo y acosada por
having eight children but it is assumed that
tener ocho hijos pero se supone que el
feminism is supporting her Why Well
feminismo la está apoyando Por qué Pues
because the person to blame for all this is her
porque el culpable de todo esto es su
abusive husband who is supposed to be
esposo abusador que se supone que la
mistreating her Valerina Far or
está maltratando valerina Far o granja
the dancer's farm is the name  from
de la bailarina es el nombre de la
Hannah New lindman's farm I hope I'm
granja de Hannah New lindman Espero que
pronouncing it correctly since we already
lo esté pronunciando bien que ya nos
know each other which has 9 million
conocemos la cual tiene 9 millones de
followers on tiktok 9 million
seguidores en tiktok 9 millones de
followers also on Instagram and more than
Seguidores también en Instagram y más de
a million and a half on YouTube which is said
un millón y medio en YouTube que se dice
soon this family at the moment with
pronto esta familia en estos momento con
what they are doing on networks they are
esto que están haciendo en redes están
earning a lot of money and
ganando muchísimo dinero y le van las
things are going very well for them Hana was born into a
cosas muy bien hana nació en una familia
Mormon family with seven brothers and one sister,
mormona con siete hermanos y una hermana
that is to say there were nine in their house the
o sea eran nueve en su casa la religión
Mormon religion also known as the Church
mormona también conocida como la iglesia
of the Latter-day Saints is a
de los Santos de los Últimos Días Es una
branch of Christianity that was born in the
rama del cristianismo que nació en el
same state in Utad more than a
mismo estado en utad hace ya más de un
century ago not to be confused with the Mennonites or
siglo no confundir con los menonitas o
Jehovah's Witnesses who have
los Testigos de Jehová que tienen reglas
much stricter rules Mormons have
mucho más estrictas los mormones han
known how to update themselves to the point that it is
sabido actualizarse al punto de que es
one of the fastest
una de las religiones con más
growing religions in Latin America for the
crecimiento en Latinoamérica por lo
same reason acaro okay It's not that I am
mismo acaro vale No es que esté yo
promoting anything or promoting or
promoviendo nada ni promocionando ni
defending okay because I am
defendiendo vale porque yo estoy en
against religions let's see against
contra de las religiones a ver en contra
against for me okay or in the
en contra para mí vale o sea en el
sense that I do not believe I am not a
sentido de que yo no creo no soy
believer in the case in  Whoever believed
creyente en el caso en el que creyera
that there was something would be completely
que hubiese algo estaría completamente
against religions, they
en contra de las religiones me parecen
all seem like half sects to me, apart from that I see them very
medio sectas todas aparte las veo muy
senseless, the truth is I think that it
sin sentido la verdad creo que
simply covers the need to believe
simplemente cubre la necesidad de creer
in something or that there is something that takes care of you and
en algo o de que hay algo que te cuida y
that's it, the truth is something that seems a
punto la verdad es algo que me parece un
little stupid to me but I respect
poco estúpido pero yo respeto a todo el
everyone who is a believer, who is religious
mundo que sea creyente que sea religioso
as long as they are people who respect
mientras que sean gente que respeten a
others. I mean, you live your religion in
los demás O sea tú vives tu religión en
your movement as long as you do not harm
tu movida mientras que no hagas daño a
others, religions that harm a
los demás religiones que hagan daño a
group or religions that harm
colectivo o religiones que hagan daño a
other people either because of gender or
otras personas ya sea por género o
because they are harmful. I am totally
porque son dañinos Estoy totalmente en
against those who condemn this religion,
contra de los condeno en esta religión
for example, they ask for the tithe that
por ejemplo piden el diezmo que
recommends giving 10% of what you earn from
recomienda dar el 10% de lo que ingrese
working to the church as alms,
trabajando a la iglesia como limosna a
unlike the Mennonites or
diferencia de los menon ninas o los
Jehovah's Witnesses, people who
Testigos de Jehová las personas que
renounce religion can continue to
renuncian a la religión Pueden seguir
accompany their family to church and they
acompañando a su familia a la iglesia y
accept people of any race or
aceptan personas de cualquier raza o
gender. Although in the case of gender they
género Aunque en el caso del género
still have great prejudices, the
siguen teniendo grandes prejuicios la
truth is also a religion that
verdad también es una religión que
promotes that people study, that
promueve que la gente estudie que la
people prepare and train because well they
gente se prepare y se forme porque bueno
consider themselves  smarter than people of
se consideran más listos que la gente de
other religions and it is assumed that the more you
otras religiones y se supone que a mayor
study and the more training the better
estudio y a mayor formación mejores son
the jobs and therefore the more tithes
los trabajos y por lo tanto más diezmo
for them let's see They are not as closed
para ellos a ver No son tan cerrados
as in other religions but it does
como en otras religiones pero sí que me
seem like a bit of a cult to me But oh well In the
parece un poco secta Pero bueno Al fin
end this one at least It seems that it
al cabo esta por lo menos Parece ser que
sort of respects others or
medio que respeta a los demás o a la
people who are outside so each one
gente que esté fuera así que cada uno
there within their freedom I understand
allá dentro de su libertad entiendo de
little ones Hanana Well she was a super
pequeñas hanana Pues fue una niña super
educated girl she focused on writing she really
educada se centró en la escritura le
liked to study and write and
gustaba mucho estudiar y escribir y
especially ballet which became
sobre todo el balet lo cual se convirtió
not only her hobby but also
no solamente en su Hobby sino además en
her dream to which she dedicated most of the
su sueño al que dedicaba la mayor parte
day and that apparently it was all a bit of a
día y eso que al parecer fue un poco
coincidence and her mother put her
casual todo y es que su madre la metió
in ballet classes because being the
en clases de ballet porque al ser la más
youngest of seven siblings she only did
pequeña de los siete hermanos solo hacía
things for boys
cosas de niños
and so her mother decided to put her
y entonces pues la madre decidió meterla
in ballet which was something that at
en el ballet que fue algo que al
first she didn't like very much
principio a ella no le hizo mucha gracia
and found it expensive but it ended up
y le resultaba costoso pero terminó
Encanto do anything And I was Getting so
Encanto do anything And I was Getting so
FR we in living room And I said m I don't want to do this
FR we in living room And I said m I
Really Bad And I
don't want to do this Really Bad And I
just want I just want to  quit
just want I just want to quit
said practice and so we practice and we practice
said practi and so we practi and we
and every after every dance cl
practi and Every after Every Dance cl
She watch and she read the steps and then
She watch and She le the steps and then
come home and practice with me and that
come home and practice With Me And that
is where I began to fall in love with dance
is Where I began to Fall In Love with
and I love that it was a challenge
Dance And I love that It was a challenge
and after a performance when I was 11
and after a performance When I was 11
years
years
old I can see you're going to juilliard
old hann I can see You're Going To
and I had no idea what that was so I
juliard And I Had no idea What that was
went home I looked up performing art
so I went home I looked up performing
school in new york and ever since that
Art school in New York and Ever since
moment when I was 11 years old I
that moment When I was 11 years old I
made a poster and put it on here and it
made a poster and and put on here come
was my dream los may to
and It was Dream of Mine los May a
fulfill her dreams and study at this
cumplir sus sueños y estudiar en esta
prestigious ballet school there she
prestigiosa escuela de ballet allí Se
fell in love with this city the city of
enamoró de esta ciudad la ciudad de los
dreams as many call it and not
sueños no que la llaman muchos y no
only did she fall in love with this city but
solamente se enamoró de esta ciudad sino
also with her studies
que a su vez también de sus estudios
as a dancer at juilliard a performing
como bailarina en juilliard una
arts university she also
universidad de artes escénicas también
participated in beauty pageants since she
participaba en reinado de belleza ya que
was pretty and well she liked to model
era guapa y Bueno le gustaba modelar
events in which her entire family
eventos en los cuales toda su familia
supported her participation later on she
apoyaba que participara más adelante
met Daniel who to this day is
conoco a Daniel el que a día de hoy es
her husband also a Mormon although from
su marido también Mormón Aunque de
family  quite a bit more modern and very
familia bastante más moderna y muy
millionaires very very millionaires in fact
millonarios muy muy millonarios de hecho
her father his father is directly the
su padre su padre directamente es el
former CEO of the airline Jet
exdirector ejecutivo de la aerolínea Jet
Blue which is a very well known airline
Blue que es una aerolínea muy conocida
in America Well in fact I would say that of the ones
en América Bueno de hecho diría que de
that most surely all of you who
las que más seguramente todos los que
are watching this video know what
estéis viendo Este vídeo sabéis de qué
company it is about they met at a
empresa se trata se conocieron en un
basketball game when she was
partido de baloncesto cuando ella tenía
22 she had already been
22 ella Ya llevaba unos cuantos de años
studying ballet in the city for a few years and he
estudiando ballet en la ciudad y él se
went crazy for her what happens is that
volvió loco por ella lo que pasa es que
according to Commenta all herself she was
ella según Comenta all misma lo fue
rejecting him on several occasions because she
rechazando en varias ocasiones porque
was very focused on her studies
estaba muy centrada en sus estudios
until he using contacts which
hasta que él utilizando contactos que
is a bit shady
esto es un poco turbio no por lo menos
not at least seen today maybe at the time in his head it sounded spectacular and romantic But when he found out about a flight that she was going to take he got the seat next to her and in this way he built trust with her here on screen I
confianza con ella por aquí en pantalla
will be putting a bit of
os estaré poniendo un poco la versión de
her version in case you want to stop the video and
ella por si queréis parar el vídeo y
read it But anyway it means that at the
leerlo Pero bueno viene a decir que al
beginning what I was telling you was that
principio lo que os iba diciendo que
although she rejected him she did like him a
aunque lo rechazaba sí que le gustaba un
little bit he didn't in fact  She found
poquillo él no que de hecho se encontró
a family that was known to Daniel
a una familia que era conocido de Daniel
at the airport and they advised her not to
en el aeropuerto y le aconsejaron que no
let him get away. Finally, she
lo dejara escapar finalmente ella lo
invited him out and three months later they got
invitó a salir y tres meses después se
married. There are also several issues with this
casaron hay también varias movidas con
thing about them getting married so quickly and
esto de que se casaran tan rápido y de
that they would soon start having children. In
que pronto empezaran a tener hijos de
fact, the pace at which she has had
hecho el ritmo al que ella mantiene
children in recent years is: She gets pregnant
hijos en los últimos años es Se embaraza
and as soon as she gives birth she gets pregnant
y tal y como pare se queda embarazado
again, okay, so it goes, it goes, there is a
otra vez vale o sea va va va teniendo de
difference in the number of children between one and the next,
diferencia los niños entre uno y otros
the pregnancy, okay, so it's not even a year and let's
el embarazo vale o sea no ni el año y a
see, regarding this, well, it could be for
ver respecto a esto pues puede ser por
several reasons. I know a lot of
varias cuestiones yo conozco a mucha
people who move out a month or two
gente que se va a vivir al mes o los dos
after being with someone when you're
meses de estar con alguien cuando eres
young, well, they do a lot of crazy things,
joven pues se hacen muchas locuras no
sometimes they go well, other times they
algunas veces que salen bien otras que
go wrong, but I think that
salen mal pero creo que también puede
the issue of religion could also be very involved
estar muy involucrado el tema de la
in this story.
religión en esta historia
[Music]
[Música]
But well, at the beginning, the pace of
Pero bueno al principio el ritmo de
getting pregnant one after the other,
quedarse embarazada una vez tras otras
well, it wasn't that constant. In fact, she did get
pues no era como tan constante De hecho
pregnant shortly after getting
sí que se quedó embarazada Al poco de
married, but she continued with her
casarse pero ella continuó con los
studies, yes, it's true that she didn't
estudios sí que es verdad que no los
want to leave them halfway, nor was she left
quería dejar a media quedándole tampoco
to finish her degree.  but I
para terminar la carrera pero también
was also very excited to be a mother, that must be
tenía mucha ilusión de ser madre eso
said. There wasn't a lot of like milk. For
decirlo there wasn't a lot of like Milk
instance, when I'd go to the grocery
for instance When i'd go to the Grocery
store, all they would have was shelf-stable milk, and it gave me a stomach ache, for example,
Store all they would have was shelf stap
every
Milk and it gave me a stomach eg Every
time I drink it, and so in Brazil, I was always trying to find these little farms, which were prevalent there,
Time I drink it and so in brazil was
there's still a lot of rural areas,
there's Still a lot of Uh rural areas
and so I was finding these little farms
and so I was finding these Little farms
to get raw milk from and fresh milk, and
to get raw Milk from and Fresh Milk and
so we started hanging out with these farmers and people that were living off
so we started hanging out with these
the land or supporting their communities, and
the Land or supporting their communities
that's really. When we fell in love with agriculture, we were like, okay,
and That's really When we fell In Love
when we go back to the United States, this is what we want to do, you know, we want to get
When we go back to the United States
into farming.
want to um get into farming
The months of pregnancy passed, and she
pasaron los meses de embarazo y ella por
finally gave birth to her first child. In May
fin dio a luz a su primer hijo en mayo
of 2012, she gave birth in a hospital in
del 2012 dio a luz en un hospital de
New York, accompanied by her husband.
Nueva York acompañada de su esposo y
She herself defined this birth as
ella misma definió este nacimiento como
a blessing from God. The truth is that
una bendición de Dios la verdad es que
neither pregnancy nor motherhood nor her
ni el embarazo ni la maternidad ni su
husband prevented her from continuing and finishing
marido le impidió continuar y terminar
her career early.  She graduated as a
con su carrera pronto se graduó como
professional dancer in New York and
bailarina profesional en Nueva York y
when she finished graduating
cuando cuando ella terminó de graduarse
since they were both a little tired of
como ambos estaban cansados un poco de
New York they decided to move
Nueva York decidieron mudarse un tiempo
to Cambridge England for a while and got married while in network city and I was dancing and he was doing an internship and we got pregnant with him. We had our first baby there and we were on the subway one day and I was nursing and I remember
a Cambridge Inglaterra dan got married
Daniel looking at me
nursing And I remember Daniel Looking at
and saying
Me And saying
like in laterra I would love to highlight
like inlaterra Me encantaría destacar
one little thing and that is that during it sparked his
una cosita y es que durante despertó su
interest in the fresh food that he
interés por la comida fresca que veía
saw there. This will be more
que se veían allí Esto va a tener más
important later on and you will already know
importancia más adelante y ya sabréis
why upon returning to the United States they
por qué a la vuelta a los Estados Unidos
stopped in Utah to visit their families
pararon en Utah a visitar a sus familias
before returning to New York and once
antes de volver a Nueva York y una vez
in New York they realized that
en Nueva York se dieron cuenta de que
New York was definitely not the
definitivamente Nueva York no era su
place for them apparently Hana had some
sitio por lo visto hana vivió alguna
unpleasant experiences on the subway
experiencia desagradable en el metro
while moving around on public transportation
mientras se movía en transporte público
with her baby and he was pretty
con su bebé y él pues estaba bastante
burned out on New York apart from
quemado de Nueva York aparte después de
having been in Utah they were
haber estado en utad pues se habían
left with the thing that
quedado como con la cosilla no de que
maybe they would be happier there so they
quizás serían más felices allí por lo
changed their lives they moved to Utah
que cambiaron su vida se mudaron a utad
in  specifically to Salt Lake City which is the
en concreto a Salt Lake City que es la
capital city there she got a
ciudad capital allí ella consiguió un
job from Monday to Thursday giving
trabajo de lunes a juev dando clases de
dance classes now let's talk a little
danza ahora vamos a hablar una cosilla
about this okay and also they could
sobre esto vale Y además se podían
combine perfectly because when
combinar perfectamente porque cuando
Daniel arrived home from work he would take care
Daniel llegaba del trabajo él se ocupaba
of the baby and she would go to work to give
del bebé y ella se iba a trabajar a dar
these classes all of this at the beginning of
estas clases todo esto a comienzo del
2013 up to where she in several blogs
2013 hasta donde ella en varios blogs
tell you that to make this video we have
deciros que para hacer este vídeo hemos
reviewed all the blogs that she has written
revisado todos los blogs que ha escrito
throughout her history on the
ella a lo largo de toda su historia en
internet and all her presence and by
internet y toda su presencia y para
then she was quite
entonces ella se encontraba bastante
happy she said that she had found
feliz decía que había encontrado la
happiness in fact there are photographs of
felicidad de De hecho hay fotografías de
her preparing ballet classes
ella preparando las clases de ballet
while her husband worked at the same
mientras que su marido trabajaba a la
time that she was taking care of the baby I mean you could
vez que estaba cuidando al bebé o sea
really see her passion in this
realmente se le notaba pasión en esto
while she was with her baby at home well there are
mientras que estaba con su bebé en casa
photographs of her rehearsing
pues hay fotografías de ella ensayando
the classes that she later taught ballet
las clases que luego impartía de balet
right now
ahora
two people one was a
mismo dos personas una fue entrenadora
beauty pageant coach in the past the
de concursos de belleza en el pasado la
other a fellow dancer with whom I
otra una compañera bailarina con la que
once danced asked me if I
alguna vez bailé me preguntaron si
was really happy to have
estaba realmente feliz de haber
given up those dreams to be where I
renunciado a eso sueños para estar donde
am today Ha I am so happy I am so at
estoy hoy Ja estoy tan feliz estoy tan
peace I have a husband who is  mine
en paz tengo un esposo que es mío para
forever together we have a beautiful baby
siempre juntos tenemos un hermoso bebé
who is full of purity and joy I get to
que está lleno de pureza y alegría puedo
spend my days with someone who is
pasar mis días con alguien que es
perfect there really can't be anything
perfecto realmente no puede haber nada
better than that I get to dance and teach classes as
mejor que eso puedo bailar y dar clases
much as possible and I love that
tanto como sea posible y me encanta eso
of course but there's nothing more
Por supuesto pero no hay nada más
rewarding than seeing my family here right
gratificante que ver a mi familia aquí
now I really feel like the
ahora mismo realmente me siento como la
luckiest girl in the world so
chica más afortunada del mundo Así que
yes I am happy about this I
sí soy feliz respecto a esto Me
would love to say something for me that you
encantaría decir algo para mí que tú
being a ballet teacher is already dedicating yourself
seas profesora de ballet ya es dedicarte
professionally to ballet in some
profesionalmente al balet de alguna
way let's see You since you were little you can
forma a ver Tú desde pequeño puedes
have various dreams you can want to be a
tener varios sueños puedes querer ser
radio presenter
presentador de radio presentador de
television presenter you can want to be Elon Mask And
televisión puedes querer ser elon Mask Y
if you really want it during your life
si realmente lo deseas durante tu vida
you prepare for it and in the end you
vas preparándote para ello y al final
can find a goal where
pues puedes encontrar una meta donde
you are happy but not necessarily
seas feliz pero No necesariamente
exactly the position that I had
exactamente el puesto con el que había
dreamed of maybe being a ballet teacher
soñado tal vez ser profesora de ballet
because it doesn't become a
pues no llega a ser bailarina
professional dancer on stage giving a
profesional encima de un escenario dando
show as such but in some
espectáculo como tal Pero de alguna
way you are dedicating yourself
forma te estás dedicando
professionally to what you like you are
profesionalmente a lo que te gusta estás
doing what you like and at the same time you
haciendo lo que te gusta y a su vez
are fulfilling your dream of being a
estás cumpliendo tu sueño de ser una
family of course It's that here the people who
familia claro Es que aquí la gente que
are criticizing this lady Well
está criticando a esta señora Bueno a
not so much this family  She and he
esta familia no tanto a ella como a él
are taking into account that here the
están teniendo en cuenta que aquí el
only dream that a person can have
único sueño que puede tener una persona
is professional. Listen to me,
es profesionalmente Escúchame yo
personally, since I was very young I
personalmente desde que era muy joven
always had the dream of having my
siempre tenía el sueño de tener mis
children and I wanted to have it as soon as possible. In
hijos y deseaba cuanto antes tenerlo De
fact, I started having it very young and
hecho yo empecé a tenerlo muy joven y
then normally, depending on how
entonces normalmente Según como se te
life goes for you. Well, there are times when you
vaya dando la vida Pues hay veces que
adapt your family dream, your dream of
adaptas tu sueño familiar tu sueño de
forming a family with the person that you
formar una familia con la persona que
love, with your professional dream, which
amas con eh tu sueño profesional que no
the professional dream doesn't always have to be
siempre el sueño profesional se tiene
fulfilled or 100%, but yes, it is usually
que cumplir o al 100% pero Sí suele
related to what you like, at
estar relacionado con lo que te gusta al
least to be happy. Okay, there are many
menos para ser feliz vale hay mucha
people, many people who, for whatever reason, have
gente muchísima gente que por lo que sea
not been lucky and have to
pues no han tenido suerte y se tienen
settle for the job that allows them to
que conformar con el trabajo con el que
survive, but it is true that
puedan sobrevivir pero sí que es verdad
I believe that every person. Well, I would
que yo creo que toda persona Bueno a mí
love to be like Disney, make a
me encantaría ser al Disney hacer
movie, and Steven Spielberg, have a
película e Steven spiber tener un
program like Pablo Motos, but for the
programa como Pablo motos pero de
moment I am quite happy because I
momento Soy bastante feliz porque me
am dedicating myself in some way to
estoy dedicando de alguna forma a
communicating and doing what I like. No,
comunicar y hacer lo que me gusta No
well, here we are facing a similar case, of
pues aquí estamos ante un caso similar
course, people are
claro es que la gente está dando por
assuming that she has abandoned her dream
hecho que ella ha abandonado su sueño
because of what she is doing now. Now,
por lo que está haciendo ahora que ahora
let's see.  what it's about and it's not
vamos a ver de lo que se trata y no está
bad at all, the truth is that he's literally
nada mal la verdad Y es que literalmente
already here leading his family with low
ya aquí llevando su familia con bajos
resources Because here things were
recursos Porque aquí las cosas le iban
regular for him, they were going very well okay And they go up to
regular iban ap purillo vale Y van hasta
the neck and he was already dedicating himself
el cuello ya se estaba dedicando
professionally to what he liked
profesionalmente a lo que le gustaba
but well we continue with the story
pero bueno continuamos con la historia
me as a dancer and me as just an individual
me as a dancer and me as just a indiv
and for a long Time It was It was so that it was It was
and for a long Time It was It was so
hard sometimes to find a
that was It was hard sometimes to find a
balance but now that I'm a Mother and a
balance but now that I'm a Mother and a
wife I don't Dance as
wife I don't Dance as
much I think Dance is
much I think Dance is
just and then  after I Had Henry um I
just and then after I Had Henry um I
knew I Wanted To Dance Still but Of
knew I Wanted To Dance Still but Of
course things changed Because I Wanted
course things changed Because I Wanted
to be a Mom that stayed and cared for
to be a Mom that stayed and cared for
him so I've teaching and going on
him so I've teaching
and but my My Passion my goals
anding on and but my My Passion my goals
and desires have changed since married
and desires have changed since married
and have a baby but It's Still Still part
and have a baby but It's Still Still
of I think the biggest Thing That
part of I think the biggest Thing That
I've learned through of course dan Is A
I've learned through of course dan Is A
huge Part Of My Life and I Wanted to dan
huge Part Of My Life and I Wanted to dan
in the Company and Maybe go to europe
in the Company and Maybe go to europe
And I Had all these Dreams but once I
And I Had all these Dreams but once I
got  married And I Had a baby my Dreams
got married And I Had a baby my Dreams
changed and  That's really good and I
changed and That's really good and I
think it's It's important for us to just put
think It's It's important for Us to Just
our trust in the lord and just kind of
put Our Trust in the lord and Just kind
ride with the journey because be
of ride with the Journey Because be
things that come up that you
things that come up that you
Last night I saw this video I loved it all of a
Anoche vi este video Me encantó de
sudden I felt like living in a
repente me dieron ganas de vivir en un
place with a lot of open space fields
lugar con mucho espacio abierto Campos
farms and a big tree with a
granjas y un gran árbol con una casa en
tree house a little different than New York
el árbol un poco diferente a Nueva York
I guess
supongo
[Music] I
[Música]
also liked it because it made me think
también me gustó porque me hizo pensar
of my handsome Daniel he does so much for
en mi lindo Daniel él hace tanto por
our family the last reason why I
nuestra familia la última razón por la
liked it well it was a reminder
que me gustó bueno fue un recordatorio
once again that I am in fact the daughter of
una vez más de que de hecho soy hija de
a heavenly father and that each one of
un padre celestial y que cada uno de
us is divine as you've heard
nosotros es divino como habéis escuchado
in his statements after watching this video he got
en sus declaraciones tras ver este vídeo
motivated up there with the idea of increasing
se motivó arriba con la idea de aumentar
his family and also wanting a
su familia y también de querer una
little house in the country Hey, it's not bad no
casita de campo Oye es que nada mal no
the truth is that the girl well has
la verdad es que la chica pues tiene
good aspirations I'm not going to deny it
buenas aspiraciones no te lo voy a negar
she took that idea as the
ella tomó como esa idea como la familia
perfect family also she went with her
perfecta además también acudía con su
husband to some classes some courses to
marido a unas clases a unos cursos para
better manage their relationship in which they
llevar mejor la relación en los que
learned among other things to cut each other's
aprendían entre otras cosas a cortarse
hair so they wouldn't have to
el pelo mutuamente para no tener que
spend  money is a good thing let's
gastarse dinero que es algo bueno
say a little special But hey, everyone can do
digamos especialito Pero bueno cada uno
what they want and I'm telling you, there are
que haga lo que quiera y te digo existe
people who watch Messi's videos
gente que ve los vídeos de Messi [__]
and here I want to show you something okay along
y aquí quiero mostraros algo vale junto
with this new dream of having a little house
a este nuevo sueño de tener una casita
in the country, she started a pretty
de campo ella comenzó un gusto bastante
cool, pretty nice taste In my opinion,
chulo bastante agradable A mi parecer
due to the vintage aesthetic, we can see in
por la estética vintage podemos ver en
her account how she was saving all kinds
su cuenta cómo iba guardando todo tipo
of images of houses decorated in this
de imágenes de casas adornadas en este
style that she liked the ideas and
estilo que le iban gustando las ideas y
she was saving them for herself, this is also
ella se las iba guardando esto también
going to have more repercussions later on
va a tomar más repercusión más adelante
okay And more sense however, her
vale Y más sentido sin embargo su
reality at this moment was a
realidad para estos momentos era un
modest apartment they were up to here
Modesto apartamento estaban hasta aquí
with the bill yes it's true that the
con la factura sí que es verdad que la
husband's family was millionaires but
familia del marido era millonaria pero
apparently they didn't give him money or
por lo visto pues no le pasaban dinero o
whatever, they didn't help him or maybe he did
lo que sea no lo ayudaban o a lo mejor
n't want to I don't know maybe he had
no quería No lo sé a lo mejor tenía
some problem with his family or he
algún problema con la familia o
just wanted to make a living
simplemente se quería buscar é la vida
the last three weeks Daniel
la papa las últimas tres semanas Daniel
went to Las Vegas for his trip to Beaux
fue a Las Vegas para su viaje a beu lax
and Henry and I couldn't live without him
y Henry y yo no podríamos vivir sin él
so we got in the car on Friday
así que nos subimos al auto el viernes
morning and arrived Just in time
por la mañana y llegamos Justo a tiempo
for his game against
para su juego contra la universidad
Chapman University  We talked about intensity Don't
Chapman hablamos de intensidad No te
worry we won by three
preocupes ganamos totalmente por tres
points but it was a heart-stopping moment
puntos pero fue un momento de infarto
exciting exciting exciting
emocionante emocionante
we've had
emocionante hemos tenido
more Henry and I are debating whether or not
más Henry y yo estamos debatiendo si
flying to New York and visiting all
volar a Nueva York y visitar a todos
our old friends there
nuestros viejos amigos de allí
might be a lot of fun but not
podría ser muy divertido pero no
really a lot of fun Because dad won't
realmente muy divertido Porque papá no
be with us anymore
estará con nosotros ya
[Music]
[Música]
[Applause] [
[Aplausos]
we'll see and now comes the climb
veremos y ahora viene la etapa de subida
to Brazil let's see the climb to
en Brasil a ver la etapa de subida en
Brazil I would say that it's the
Brasil Yo sí que diría que es la etapa
toughest stage of his life or at least the one he had the
más chunga de su vida o por lo menos la
worst time of at least the first
que peor lo pasó por lo menos el primer
year It turns out that Daniel gets a
año Resulta ser que a Daniel le sale un
job in Brazil and while she's
trabajo en Brasil y a ambos estando ella
pregnant with their second child they move to
embarazada de su segundo hijo se mudan a
Brazil the problem is that the job
Brasil el problema es que el trabajo
well the apartment that they can
bueno el apartamento que pueden
afford is about an hour and a
permitirse está más o menos a una hora y
half away from Daniel's job
media de camino del trabajo de Daniel
So Daniel often wouldn't go
Por lo cual Daniel muchas veces no iba a
home to sleep to save himself those three
dormir a casa para ahorrarse esas tres
hour commute
horas de camino de ida y vuelta por lo
so they spent very little time together as a
cual pasaban muy poco tiempo juntos como
family she was a little bitter
familia ella estaba un poco amargada
normal logical normal and on top of that in a country
normal lógico normal y encima en un país
where he didn't know anyone and  it's
en el que no conocía a nadie y no es el
yours so if motherhood and being a
suyo así que si la maternidad y el ser
wife means that I'm packing up and
esposa significan que estoy empacando y
moving to another country where I can support
mudándome a otro país donde puedo apoyar
my husband while he tries to support
a mi esposo mientras él trata de apoyar
this family of ours yes it probably
a esta familia nuestra si probablemente
means a lot of days of speaking in
significa muchos días hablando en
baby talk to my two boys
lenguaje infantil con mis dos hijos
because I don't know the language to talk to
porque no sé ese idioma para hablar con
anyone else then so be it yesterday
nadie más entonces que así sea ayer
Daniel took the afternoon off from
Daniel se tomó la tarde libre en el
work and we went out for a walk
trabajo y salimos a dar un paseo
maybe yesterday at lunch I
puede que ayer durante el almuerzo haya
had a major meltdown and I told
tenido un colapso importante y le dije a
Daniel I was going to run away it was a
Daniel que me iba a escapar fue un
meltdown man so he loaded everyone into the
colapso hombre así que subió a todos al
car and we got ready to hit the
auto y nos dispusimos a presionar el
reset button we drove and
botón de reinicio condujimos y
drove we talked and we cried and Daniel
condujimos hablamos y lloramos y Daniel
held my hand tight Charles
me agarró fuerte de la mano Charles
slept and Henry watched the trucks on
durmió y Henry observó los camiones en
the freeway
la autopista
everything is really good and the time with
todo está realmente bien y el tiempo con
Daniel to talk was what I needed
Daniel para hablar era lo que necesitaba
after almost a year Daniel got a
luego de casi un año Daniel consiguió un
much better apartment 4 minutes from
apartamento mucho mejor a 4 minutos de
her work they moved there spectacular I
su trabajo se mudaron allí espectacular
mean the change doesn't make sense
o sea el cambio no tiene sentido
obviously with this the situation for
evidentemente con esto la situación para
her and the depression she had improved
ella y la depresión que tenía mejoró
a lot plus the place had a
bastante además en el lugar había una
Mormon church she met some people that she
iglesia mormona conoció a gente con la
hangs out with and her friends were
que pasa el rato y su amistades tenía
really close  a shopping center
muy cerca un centro comercial la hermana
Daniel's sister also settled there
de Daniel también se instaló por allí la
things were getting better for them they were
cosa para ellos Fue mejorando se
able to take some
pudieron permitir darse algunas
vacations for example Punta Cana
vacaciones por ejemplo puntacana
Dominican Republic or also on one
República Dominicana o también en una
occasion to Rio de Janeiro to see the
ocasión a Río de Janeiro a ver el
World Cup in Brazil in 2014 Although it is
mundial de Brasil en 2014 Aunque sí que
true that they were a little uncomfortable there
es verdad que allí se incomodaron un
because people asked
poco porque la gente como que le pedía
her a lot of photos because she was pretty she didn't
muchas fotos a ella por ser guapa no le
like the atmosphere
gustaba mucho el ambiente que había para
there with a baby there was only one
estar allí con un bebé solamente haba un
game because she didn't like
partido porque tampoco que le gustara
the atmosphere there
mucho el ambiente que había por allí
with a couple of babies very much according to
para estar con un par de bebés según
her words she had to
palabras de ella tuvo que estar
cover her children's eyes on several
tapándole los ojos a sus hijos en varias
occasions so that the children wouldn't see
ocasiones para que los hijos no vieran
indecent things and she also managed to
cosas indecentes y también consiguió
sign up for a valet class with
apuntarse a una clase de valet con la
which she passed the time doing her H
que pasaba el tiempo haciendo su H
too and not just her Hobby because she
también y no solamente su Hobby porque
came to present several
llegó a presentar varios espectáculos
Nutcracker shows there in Brazil things
del cascanueses allí en Brasil la cosas
weren't bad at all The move is that on
no estaba nada mal La Movida es que el
December 13, 2015 Daniel's boss
13 de diciembre de 2015 el jefe de
invited them to a farm where he
Daniel los invitó a una Finca en la que
lived with his parents two 80
vivía con sus padres dos personas de 80
year old people who worked on a farm  There
años que trabajaban en una granja allí
in Brazil, Hann was very
en Brasil a hann le llamó mucho la
interested in the idea that this
atención el tema de que este matrimonio
elderly couple was self-sufficient
de la tercera edad fuera autosuficiente
with their own resources, having their
con sus propios recursos teniendo su
own meat, their own eggs, which is a bit of a
propia carne sus propios huevos lo que
farm. Not
viene a ser una una granja no
completely from their land. They only went to
completamente De su tierra solo iban al
town once a month to buy
pueblo una vez al mes para comprar
some cleaning products, sugar, and
algunos productos de limpieza azúcar y
rice. They made their own cheese, they raised their
arroz hacían su propio queso criaban su
own meat, they milked their own cows, they
propia came ordeñan sus propias vacas
had their own garden. You get the
tenían su propio jardín ya te haces una
idea, why this thing caught his
idea por lo que esta movida llamó su
interest, adding it to the idea that he already understood from the
interés sumándolo a la idea que ya pilló
video from a few years ago, and it
con la del vídeo de hace algunos años y
can be said that it was his inspiration
se puede afirmar que fue su inspiración
and his love for agriculture.
y que su amor por la agricultura
And more and
and more and
more. Because there wasn't a lot of milk, for
more Because wasn't a lot of um like
instance, when I'd go to the
Milk for instance When i'd go to the
grocery store, all they would have was shelf-stable milk,
Grocery Store all they would have was um
and it gave me a stomach ache.
shelf stable Milk and it gave me a
Every time I drank it,
stomach cake Every Time I drink it and
I was always trying to find these
so in brazil I was Always trying to find
little farms. Which were
these Little farms Which were prevalent
prevalent there, there's a lot of
are prevalent there there's a lot of
rural areas, and so I was finding these
rural areas and so I was finding these
little farms to get raw milk from and fresh milk, and so
Little farms to get raw Milk from and
we started hanging out
Fresh Milk and so we started hanging out
with these farmers.  and people that were
with these Farmers and people that were
living in the land.
living
Love with agriculture. Go backed. Do
landun Love with
you know, we get into farming. Support our family. We don't just want to do like a hobby farm. We want it to be like our livelihood. And so, yeah. That's really. Where it all blossomed was. When we were in Brazil,
backed Do you know we get into farming
we were in Paulo. Also,
weing in brazil we were in Paulo además
there in Brazil, she got a
allí en Brasil también consiguió un
ballet job that only took her
trabajo de balet que lo ocupaba tan solo
3 hours, which was
3 horas lo cual podía venirle
perfect for combining with her
perfectamente para combinarlo con su
personal life as a mother and enjoying
vida personal como madre y disfrutar de
her little ones. Although it's true that she
sus pequeños Aunque sí que es verdad que
wasn't very happy in that job,
no estaba muy a gusto en ese trabajo
not because she didn't like what she was
pero no porque no le gustase lo que
doing, but because her
hacía sino porque tenía todo el tiempo
mind was at home all the time because of the children.
la mente en su casa por los niños mes
Next month I'm participating in a
que viene participaré en una competencia
ballet competition for a small company here,
de ballet para una pequeña compañía aquí
which means that I have rehearsals. I
lo que significa que tengo ensayos me
love to dance and I love having
encanta bailar y me encanta tener
little breaks every now and then to
pequeños descansos de vez en cuando para
have some time for myself, which I need.
tener un tiempo para mí que necesito
But these mandatory 3-
pero estos ensayos obligatorios de 3
hour rehearsals are killing me. My
horas Me están matando mi cerebro de
mom brain stops working after the
mamá deja de funcionar después de la
second hour and all I can think about
segunda hora y todo lo que puedo pensar
is my little ones. George is hungry. Will
es en mis pequeños George tiene hambre
Charles know how to pee in the toilet
sabrá Charles Cómo hacer pipí en el baño
without me? Henry keeps playing with the
sin mí Henry sigue jugando con el
stupid iPad.  As soon as the
estúpido iPad Tan pronto como termina el
rehearsal ends and apparently this situation
ensayo y por lo visto esta situación
added to the death of her grandmother
sumada a la muerte de su abuela pues la
led her to think about going back to utat pause what the
llevó a pensarse volver a utat pausa qué
[ __ ] is this I mean what the [ __ ] is this I
[__] es esto O sea qué [__] es esto
understand that each culture is a world no
entiendo que cada cultura es un mundo no
and that countries are different but
y que los países somos diferentes pero
[ __ ] someone caught my attention
[__] me ha llamado la atención alguien
taking a picture like he
haciéndose una fotografía así como que
's posing with I don't know with the
está posando con yo que sé con la fuente
Treviso fountain not there in Italy and he's
de trevis no allí en Italia y está
posing with his grandmother's coffin for
posando con el ataúd de su abuela para
2017 the project known
2017 nace el proyecto conocido a día de
today as the Balerina Farm channel was born his
hoy como el canal balerina Farm su
business on
negocio en redes
social networks ascor
sociales ascor
so I felt comfortable Being on social
so I felt comfortable Being on social
media and sharing Our Story Daniel Still Had
media and sharing Our Story Daniel Still
his day Job and we started off with
Had his day Job and we started off with
Four pigs there was One Boy Pig and
Four pigs there was One Boy Pig and
three three girl pigs and we started you
three three girl pigs and we started you
know documenting what It was like as as City
know documenting what It was like as as
Kids you know Getting into Farm
City Kids you know Getting into Farm
life and I remember When we we Had Those
life and I remember When we we Had Those
First crop of piglets pigs raised ready to to
First crop of piglets pigs raised ready
sell there was so much interest
to to sell there was so much interest
and the meat Because these people haden was rais
and the meat Because these people haden
they knew Where was coming I
was rais they knew Where was coming yo
think or at least for me the subject of that
creo o al meno para m el tema de que
of the  social networks and what they
esto de las redes sociales y a lo que se
do today, we're
dedican a día de hoy que estamos
talking about channels with millions of
hablando de canales con millones de
followers, they are hyper mega known, they
Seguidores son hiper mega conocidos
earn a lot of money, I mean, you can't
ganan muchísimo dinero o sea no os
imagine how much I think all of
podéis imaginar cuánto yo creo que todo
this is apart from her idea, managed
esto es aparte de idea de ella manejado
by her talent. So there
por su talento Así que ahí ya se me
the issue of gender roles falls apart for me a bit,
desmonta un poco el tema de los roles de
eh. And how can we intuit that it's
género eh Y cómo podemos intuir que es
her idea, man, because the truth is, if
idea de ella hombre porque la verdad si
the husband were an abuser, eh, or a
el marido fuera un abusador eh o un
narcissist or whatever, any
narcisista o yo que sé cualquier movida
of this stuff, I understand that they wouldn't have
de esta entiendo que no lo habrían
named the farm after the
bautizado a la granja con el nombre del
hobby that she likes. And here we have to
Hobby que a ella le gusta y aquí tenemos
remember two things. On the one hand,
que recordar dos cositas Por una parte
what I told you earlier about the trip to
lo que os dije anteriormente del viaje a
England in which she was struck by
Inglaterra en el que a ella le llamó la
the fresh food that was
atención los alimentos frescos que se
sold on the street. And secondly, and I think it's
vendían en la calle y segundo y creo que
also very important, the
también muy importante la decoración
vintage decoration of the house, which we can
vintage de la casa que podemos verla
usually see in all of her videos, or
habitualmente en todos sus vídeos o en
almost all of them, at least the ones she makes
casi todos por lo menos los que hace
inside the house, no, and about the farm, it
dentro de la casa no y de la granja no
's not because she wants to live in the 1800s
es porque quiera vivir en los años 1800
or anything like that.  It's her
ni nada por el estilo ni es idea del
husband's idea, and she doesn't have the house to
esposo tampoco la casa la tiene al gusto
her liking, just like the ones she's been saving
de ella idea tal y como las que guardaba
on Pinterest since 2013. Every
desde el año 2013 en su Pinterest cada
time she found something she liked,
vez que encontraba algo que le gustaba
at the beginning of this whole social
al principio de todo el rollo este de
media thing, her husband continued working. I
las redes su esposo siguió trabajando Me
imagine it's because you don't trust that
imagino que porque no te fías no de que
this will have stability. I think it happens
esto tenga estabilidad creo que nos pasa
to all of us who are dedicated to social
un poco a todos los que nos dedicamos a
media, you don't know how long it's going to
las redes que no sabes cuánto tiempo va
last. No, this is very ephemeral,
a durar no esto es muy efímero de
suddenly tomorrow maybe it will occur to you to
repente mañana a lo mejor se os ocurre
suddenly stop seeing me and I have
dejar de verme de repente y no tengo
nothing. No, in fact, at the beginning it wasn't that they
nada No de hecho al principio no es que
earned much and this effort on the
ganaran mucho y este esfuerzo por parte
husband's part was to be able to continue
del esposo era para poder seguir
building the farm until they
construyendo la granja hasta que la
finished it, but things kept moving forward, they
terminaron pero la cosa fue avanzando
kept moving forward and it was also good.
fue avanzando y fue tamban bien que
Although the house is decorated in a
aunque la casa esté adornada así tipo
vintage style, we can see appliances
vintage podemos ver electrodomésticos
that are very expensive. In fact, there is an oven
que son carísimo De hecho hay un horno
that costs more than $30,000, this
que cuesta más de $30,000 esto quiere
means that things are going very well for him. Of course,
decir que las cosas le van muy bien y
on this farm, I understand that they
claro en esta granja entiendo que
also sell food. According to social media, it is said
también venden alimentos se habla según
that, well, apart from the 100
la redes de que Bueno aparte de 100
million that the family is supposed to inherit
millones que se supone que heredará a la
when  parents die I
familia cuando los padres fallezcan
understand that his parents who are
entiendo que los padres de él que son
millionaires Hana alone already has a
millonarios Solamente hana ya tiene un
capital of more than 2 million dollars
capital de más de 2 millones de dólares
and the farm would currently move
y la granja movería en la actualidad
this according to the media okay I don't know if it's
esto según medios vale No sé si es al
100% but let's be an estimate about
100% pero vamos ser una estimación unos
6 million dollars in capital
6 millones de dólares en capital
[Music]
[Música]
B
B
of course let's see prog grenlandia is
claro a ver prog grenlandia está
criticizing well first I was
criticando bueno primero estaba
criticizing her for promoting these
criticando a ella por promover estos
gender stereotypes and the
estereotipos de género y de la familia
traditional family that prog grenlandia also doesn't like
tradicional que tampoco le gusta a prog
and now they are
grenlandia y ahora pues están
criticizing me that he is an abuser who
criticándome que es un abusador que la
has her locked up in a glass prison
tiene encerrada en una cárcel de cristal
without sense okay I mean if someone
sin sentido vale o sea si alguien
considers that this woman or this
considera que esta mujer o que esta
family well are not successful as such they do
familia bueno no tienen éxito como tal
not have a privileged life of success
no tienen una vida privilegiada de éxito
because she is not dedicating herself to being a
porque no está ella dedicándose a ser
professional dancer it is that you do
bailarina profesional es que tú sí que
dedicate yourself to being a dancer and you have fallen
te dedicas a ser bailarín y te has caído
headfirst down the stairs of the
de cabeza por las escaleras del
stage okay I mean literally they have
escenario vale o sea literalmente tienen
a life of success family success a
una vida de éxito exito familiar una
family that has been around for many years with
familia que lleva un montón de años con
a lot of  children who are surely
un montón de hijos que seguramente sean
super happy, don't lack anything and I'm not
super felices no le falten De nada y no
saying this just for the money but
lo digo solamente por el dinero sino
because by dedicating yourself to what you
porque al dedicarte a lo que a ti te
like you also have the time that you
gusta tienes también el tiempo que te da
want, you are your own boss, you spend with your
la gana eres tu propio jefe pasas con tu
family the time that you want if today
familia el tiempo que te apetece si hoy
suddenly you t do something okay
de repente se te t algo lo haces vale
you can dedicate yourself to your children
puedes dedicarte a tus hijos a día de
today there are many people who are working
hoy hay mucha gente que está trabajando
surely the majority of those who are
seguramente la mayoría de los que estáis
watching this video and you are under schedules
viendo Este vídeo y estáis bajo horarios
under bosses under [ __ ] because you have to
bajo jefes bajo [__] porque tenéis que
take the salary home and you can't
llevar el sueldo a casa y no podéis
be with your children as you would
estar con vuestros hijos lo que os
like you can't sleep with your
gustaría no podéis dormir con vuestro
child as you would like you are with the
hijo lo que os gustaría estás con los
animals that you love you are earning 7,000
animales que amas estás ingresando 7,000
times more than what you would earn being a
veces más que lo que ingresaría siendo
dancer I really don't understand [ __ ] people I
bailarina yo no entiendo a la [__] gente
mean people are going to the
de verdad O sea la gente se leev va a la
[ __ ] [ __ ] pot we live right now in a
[__] olla vivimos ahora mismo en una
current situation that is a [ __ ] crazy
actualidad que es una [__] fumada ida de
and we have to exterminate many
olla y que hay que exterminar muchas
pests okay And a lot of nonsense But anyway I
plagas vale Y muchas tonterías Pero
wanted to tell you the true
bueno os quería exponer la verdadera
story behind Valerina Farm Because
historia detrás de valerina Farm Porque
many of you have come to me  ask and
muchos me habéis venido a preguntar y
really This is the true story
realmente Esta es la verdadera historia
yes it is true that you can see some
sí que es verdad que puedes ver alguna
things from the husband like the click
cosa por parte del marido como el click
that at the beginning not of the apron that I
que al principio no del delantal que
understand that when she has edited it and
entiendo que cuando ella lo ha editado y
has put the joking tone it is because it is
le ha puesto el tono de broma es porque
a joke we ourselves at home
es un cachondeo nosotros mismos en casa
once gave my mother
le regalamos una vez por Rey a mi madre
a coffee maker for King when she was
una cafetera cuando ella estaba
expecting I think she was expecting a
esperando creo que estaba esperando un
computer and we played the joke on her by
ordenador y le hicimos la broma de
giving her the coffee maker and she got
regalarle la cafetera y se enfadó
very angry and yes it is true that there are
muchísimo y sí que es verdad que hay
several clips where we can see the husband
varios clis donde podemos ver al marido
who is a little lazy in the sense that he does
que es un poco vago en el sentido de que
not do the tasks like her but
no hace las tareas igual que ella pero
well maybe for many years
bueno a lo mejor durante muchos años Fue
He was the one who cured to get ahead in the
él el que curó para sacar adelante a la
family and now he is worse at these
familia y ahora pues se le da peor estas
things on the farm or simply the
cosas de la granja o simplemente los
clicks that are seen Well they are not the most
clics que se ven Pues no son los más
appropriate when he makes the criticisms they
apropiados cuando hace las críticas
take the worst clips but really to
cogen los clips peores pero realmente a
me from what we are investigating in
mí por lo que estamos investigando en
these last hours it seems that they are
estas últimas horas me parece que son
a family that lives an
una familia que viven una vida
enviable life and that surely That is why there is
envidiable y que seguramente Por eso hay
armpit hair pulling family
tiradera de pelos de sobaco familia
tell me what you think I will be
decidme ustedes qué pensáis os estaré
reading the comments box I am  It's a
leyendo la caja de comentarios estoy
pleasure to be back with
encantado de estar aquí de vuelta con
you all. Tomorrow I have another nose job
ustedes mañana me opero la nariz otra
and I have to touch something,
vez que me tengo que tocar una cosilla
okay, because I can't breathe well. So maybe
vale porque no respiro bien Así que a lo
I'll disappear again for a couple of
mejor desaparezco otra vez un par de
days, okay, because it's a health issue,
días vale porque es un tema de salud
but I hope to be with you all at
pero espero estar con ustedes pues como
the latest on the weekend, okay, or
muy tarde el fin de semana vale o en
live, maybe not recording videos, we'll
directos a lo mejor no grabando vídeos
see. I send you all a big kiss and
ya veremos os mando un beso muy fuerte y
bye, my handsome, handsome guys. See you later.
chao guapos guapísimos míos nos vemos